While viewing message definitions and topic information can be informative,
メッセージ定義とトピック情報の表示が有益である一方で
sometimes the best way to understand what is going on is to look
進行状況の把握に最適な方法はメッセージがトピックに出力される際に
at the messages themselves as they are published to a topic.
メッセージそのものを確認することです
For example, when the turtle rotates left and
たとえば亀が左右に回転するときは
right which axis is it actually rotating about?
どの軸が実際に回転しているでしょうか?
And what are the units of rotation?
また回転の単位は何でしょうか?
And are rotations expressed in terms of radians or degrees?
回転はラジアン単位ですか それとも度単位ですか?
To get the answer to these questions,
この質問の答えを出すために
You can use the command rostopic echo.
rostopic echo コマンドを使用します
Let's dive right into its usage.
それでは実際にやってみましょう
Rostopic, echo,
Rostopic echo
and then the name of the topic forward
トピック名として /turtle1
slash turtle one forward slash command underscore vel.
/cmd_vel とします
If you've forgotten the name of the topic,
トピック名を忘れてしまった場合
you can easily find it by using
rostopic list を使用して簡単に探すことができます
the command rostopic list which you were introduced to earlier in the screentask.
これはスクリーンタスクで前に導入しました
When you hit enter, the terminal cursor will move to a new line
enter をクリックすると ターミナルカーソルが新しいラインに移動し
and it will appear as though nothing has happened. Fear not though.
何も起こっていないように見えますそのままお待ちください
Rostopic echo is simply waiting for a message to be published on the command vel topic.
Rostopic echo は com_vel トピックに出力されるメッセージを待っているだけです
In order to publish a message to the topic,
トピックにメッセージが出力されるために
we must jump all the way back to the console window for
turtle_teleop_key ノード用のコンソールウィンドウまで
the turtle underscore teleop underscore key node.
さかのぼります
And I'm now going to hit the left arrow key.As expected,
ここで左矢印をクリックすると 予想したとおり
the turtle turned counter-clockwise by some angle for about one second.
亀は 1 秒間ある角度で反時計回りに回転しました
I'd estimate that the actual number is somewhat maybe like greater than 90 degrees,
実際はだいたい 90 度以上 135 度より少ない角度を
but perhaps less than 135 degrees.
想定しています
Let's go back to the rostopic echo terminal and see what happened.
rostopic echo ターミナルに戻り どうなるか見てみましょう
And as you can see we've caught a message.
ご覧のように メッセージが表示されます
All of the velocity components are zero with
角速度の z 成分を除き
the exception of the z component of the angular velocity.
すべての速度成分は 0 です
Here we see a value of two.
ここに 2.0 の数値が確認できます
This tells us, that when the turtle rotates counterclockwise,
これは亀が反時計回りに
it is doing so around the z axis.
Z 軸の周りに回転することを意味します
The magnitude of the velocity,
動きに関連した単位を意味する
tells us that the units associated with the movement are
速度の大きさはおそらく 1 秒あたりのラジアン単位となります
probably in radians per second. How did I get there?
どのようにして得られたのでしょうか?
Well, a quick math check will tell us that two radians corresponds to
簡単な演算により 2 つのラジアンが
approximately 114.6 degrees. And there we have it.
約 114.6 度に換算されることがわかりますさ できました
You should now have some understanding about rostopic echo and
これで rostopic echo についてと トピック内での
how it can be used for investigating messages passing over a topic.
調査メッセージの使用方法について 理解できたと思います
As a side note, If this unit's investigation seems a little bit contrived,
追記として この単位の調査は
that's because it certainly was.
確かに少し工夫を要します
Like any sensible engineers,
賢明な技術者のように ROS のディベロッパーは
the developers of Ros have elected to standardize around S-I units wherever applicable.
適用可能であれば S-I 単位の標準化を選択しました
Which is to say, length is measured in meters.
すなわち 長さはメートル単位で測定します
Mass is measured in kilograms,
重量はキログラム単位で
time is measured in seconds and angles are measured in radians and so on.
時間は秒で測定し 角度はラジアンで測定します
You've now completed a brief tour of the Ros command line tools.
これで ROS コマンドラインツールに関する概要説明を終わります
Armed with this knowledge and
この知識を身につけて
the general understanding of the Ros communications architecture,
ROS コミュニケーションアークテクチャーの概要を理解することで
you should be prepared to move on to the next
次のステップ 最初の catkin ワークスペースへ進むための
step - setting up your first catkin workspace.
準備ができました